efm.co.in 2019-06-16

# Recharge Duniya » Privacy Policy

Being a collaborative community the top-priority of Recharge Duniya will always be the relationship with its community. Recharge Duniya is therefore firmly committed to the security and protection of the personal integrity of our Users of the Services (as defined in the Terms of Service) and their contacts.

This Privacy Policy describes what personal information You may share with Recharge Duniya, as data controller, and other Users when activating and using the Recharge Duniya Services, how Recharge Duniya receives, collects and uses this data and how You may opt-out at any time, altogether preventing use of the data shared via the Services.

Information Collected and Received

Installation and Use

When you install and use the Recharge Duniya Apps, Recharge Duniya will collect, process and retain personal information from You and any devices You may use in Your interaction with our Services. This information may include the following: geo-location, Your IP address, device ID or unique identifier, device manufacturer and type, device and hardware settings, ID for advertising, ad data, operating system, operator, IMSI, connection information, screen resolution, usage statistics, device log and event information, incoming and outgoing calls and messages, times and date of calls, duration of calls, version of the Recharge Duniya Apps You use and other information based on Your interaction with our Services. Recharge Duniya may use the information collected from, and in connection with, all of our services to provide, maintain, and improve them, to develop new ones, and to protect Recharge Duniya and its users. Recharge Duniya also uses this information to provide you with tailored content, such as search results and advertisements more relevant to You.

For details regarding permission usage in connection with installation on the Android platform, please see the Recharge Duniya FAQ at www.Recharge Duniya.com/support.

User Profile

Where the User registers a user profile in the Recharge Duniya Apps and via SMS or inbound call verification confirms being the holder of a certain number, the information up-loaded to the profile section of the Recharge Duniya Apps will be received and stored by Recharge Duniya until the User changes or deletes such data or terminates the Services. Compulsory information when creating a profile page is the User’s first name, last name and phone number and additional information that may be provided at the User’s option include, but is not limited to, photo, gender, street address and zip code, country of residence, email address, professional website, Facebook page, Twitter address and a short status message. Recharge Duniya may supplement the information provided or collected with information from third parties and add it to information provided by You. For example, collection and use of demographic information that is publicly available and additional contact information as allowed by applicable national laws.

Please note that any content uploaded to and displayed in the user profile by the User is not moderated by Recharge Duniya and is not protected under the Swedish Fundamental Law on Freedom of Expression. The User is solely liable for the publication of such content. Please see the Terms of Service for further information regarding protection under the Swedish Fundamental Law on Freedom of Expression.

Identifiers

In addition, You may provide us with Your user identifier information regarding certain third party services, i.e. Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Twitter, necessary for the application to interoperate with such third party services. In that case Recharge Duniya will store and process also that information (and also a mapped photo where applicable), for as long as You use the Services and will not use this information for any other purpose than required in order to obtain interoperability and functionality in relation to such third party services. Please note that we never store any passwords to the mentioned third party services.

Contact Information

Where the Recharge Duniya Apps are obtained from other sources than Apple App Store or Google Play, You may share the names, numbers and email addresses contained in Your device’s address book (“Contact Information”) with Recharge Duniya for the purpose described below under Enhanced Search. If you provide us with personal information about someone else, you confirm that they are aware that You have provided their data and that they consent to our processing of their data according to our Privacy Policy.

Where the Recharge Duniya Apps are obtained from Apple App Store or Google Play, we will only use permitted Contact Information to make our Services more relevant to You and Your engagement with the Recharge Duniya community.

In addition to Contact Information, if You choose to activate use of a third party social network service, such as Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn or Twitter, within the Recharge Duniya Apps, Recharge Duniya may up-load, store and use the list of identifiers associated with said services linked to the Contact Information in order to enhance the results shared with other Users.

Please note that no other Contact Information than the phone numbers and thereto attached names and email addresses will be received, stored and used from the User’s address book. Other numbers or information that may be contained in your device’s phone book will be filtered away and will therefore not be stored or used by Recharge Duniya. Addresses, passwords and credit card numbers and any other similar information will automatically be prevented from being entered into the Recharge Duniya database by our safety algorithms, that filters any numbers and other information stored in the phone book in a number sequence not compatible with that used for telephone numbers. Please also note that You can always choose not to share Contact Information with Recharge Duniya and if You have shared information and changed Your mind, You can easily delist Your number or opt-out to render your entire Contact Information unavailable for search in the database for Enhanced Search.

Name tagging

We may also associate a name with a phone number through the name tagging functionality, which allows a User who receives a call from a phone number which is not associated with a name in the Recharge Duniya database to indicate a name to be associated with that number. A name will only be associated with a number through this functionality if a sufficient number of independent Users, based on our algorithm, have indicated the same name for the relevant number.

Call Block

Where a User within the Services reports a phone number as spam, Recharge Duniya stores that phone number in combination with the User’s RegisterID in order to maintain the User’s spam list online but also for the purpose of building a community based spam blocking directory. On the Android platform, the User can also add a name to the phone number in question that will only be visible to that User.

RDuedialer

With the rddialer app and functionality You are provided with a fast and smart dialer for Your phone that, among other features, will provide instant search results from Your phonebook, populate unidentified numbers in your call log and provide unique search results from the Recharge Duniya database. Apart from Your location when performing an active search, and exclusively for the purpose of optimizing the search result, no further data or information than accounted for in the Terms and this Privacy Policy will be processed when You use the rddialer app (and such location data will not be stored).

rdmessenger

With the rdmessenger app You are provided with an SMS and MMS messaging service. In order to facilitate the delivery of your messages through the rdmessenger app, Recharge Duniya may store your messages in encrypted form for a limited period of time. However, Recharge Duniya does not monitor the content of such messages.

Use, Sharing and Disclosure of User and Contact Information

Information related to the User or Contact Information will be used to:

(a) display the name associated with a certain number at a manual number search against the Recharge Duniya database,

(b) automatically display the caller’s name when a call is received, as enabled by the Enhanced Search functionality, as described below, to Users who have activated that functionality, and indicate possible common connections with the caller or when an incoming call may be spam,

(c) display the “who viewed my profile” and “availability” functionalities of the Services,

(d) provide selected Recharge Duniya partners with limited information in order to enhance user experience, service functionality and data accuracy, provided that these partners adhere to strict confidentiality provisions no less protective of your rights than the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy,

(e) enable the Recharge Duniya Name Search, as described below, to Users who have activated that functionality,

(f) contact You from Recharge Duniya for verification purposes or with information pertaining to the Services, e.g. newsletter e-mails and similar notifications, and verify provided User Profile information with third party providers,

(g) deliver messages through the rdmessenger app,

(h) enable You to use and share Your user information in connection with Your use of third party services,

(i) customize, maintain, measure, improve our Services and develop new ones,

(j) personalize, measure and improve our advertising and use geo-location information to provide You with location based information and services (such as more relevant advertising, search results and other personalized content).

Enhanced Search functionality and database

To improve the Services, Recharge Duniya has created a searchable database where the Users generate the content and via the Enhanced Search functionality are offered access to this database, containing Contact Information from those Users who permit such aggregation. In return these Users are allowed to access to the database by querying it. Queries against the database are only allowed through the Recharge Duniya Services by Users who have explicitly approved of the Service's functionality and integrity restrictions as contained in the Recharge Duniya Terms of Service, the API License Addendum and this Privacy Policy.

The queries against the Recharge Duniya Enhanced Search database are processed only if a numeric phone number is attributed to the query and only if no results are published by an associated or partnering database of Recharge Duniya. The response given to the queried number will be the associated name to that number, if any name is available.

It is important to notice the following distinctions. As an integrity and security measure, only numeric queries are allowed against the Recharge Duniya database for Enhanced Search, i.e. there will be no result to a name query. Name searches may, however, give result via the Services if a partnering or associated database to Recharge Duniya has numbers available to the name queries. The Users contributing to Enhanced Search can therefore rely on that the Contact Information provided, as a personal integrity precaution, will not enable anyone searching for the number to a certain person direct access to that number. In some cases, Users may, however, use the Services to forward a request to a named person in order to get in touch, please see below about the Recharge Duniya Name Search service.

The database may also – via a “social graph” algorithm - be used to show the User what other Users he or she, directly or indirectly, has in common with another User and to suggest other contacts they may have in common. Please note that, if You are presented as a person that the User who made the query may know or as a “similar” person, some of Your profile information entered by you, excluding phone number, will be disclosed to such User.

Name Search

Your name and telephone number and any other information You choose to submit on Your User Profile will be visible to the person You reach out to when requesting a contact via the Recharge Duniya Name Search service. Your request will be forwarded to that person via an SMS and he or she may choose to share the phone number with You (of which You in such case will be informed of via a push notification), or not, at his or her own discretion, but may also block further request from You or to opt-out of the service altogether at any time. Nobody will under any circumstances receive more than three contact requests via the Recharge Duniya Name Search service during any 24 hours and has anybody received nine requests during the last 72 hours, that person will not receive additional requests for the next 72 hours. Excessive requests not delivered will be put on hold in chronological order, unless the recipient actively allows further requests to be forwarded.

Via the Recharge Duniya Name Search service You may be recommended, via a push notification, when there are new contacts that you may know and be interested in getting in touch with.

Opt-Out and Delist Numbers

If a User chooses to disable the Enhanced Search functionality, the Contact Information made available by that User is disabled and will thereafter not be accessible for queries. If any persons do not wish to have their names and phone numbers made available through the Enhanced Search or Name Search functionalities, they can exclude themselves from further queries by notifying Recharge Duniya via its website at www.Recharge Duniya.com or as set forth in the contact details below.

Miscellaneous

In addition to the above Recharge Duniya may disclose information related to the Users and Contact Information if we believe such action is necessary to:

(a) comply with the law, or legal process served on us;

(b) protect and defend our rights or property (including the enforcement of our agreements); or

(c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Users or members of the public.

Recharge Duniya may share Your personal data with trusted third party service providers and partners. Recharge Duniya will always require these third parties to take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect your personal data and traffic data and to observe the relevant legislThe following is a description of how Recharge Duniya may share information about You with trusted third party partners:ation.

The following is a description of how Recharge Duniya may share information about You with trusted third party partners:

1\. Recharge Duniya uses a third party partner company in order to send You or a third party you wish to contact SMS when you use the Services. In order to send you the SMS, we send the third party company Your and the relevant third party’s phone numbers. This third party SMS partner is contractually obligated only to use these phone numbers for the transmission of requested SMS.

2\. Recharge Duniya may use Push Notification Services to notify you about up-dates and important information. In such cases, Your phone number may be part of the notification. This message is sent to the push notification service provider, for delivery to Your device. You may, however, at any time-opt out or disable push notifications in the Recharge Duniya Apps.

3\. Recharge Duniya may allow you to use third party services to create your user profile or log in to use our Services, share information with such third parties, or to connect your user profile with the respective third parties. Those third parties may automatically provide us with access to certain personal information retained by them about You (e.g., content viewed by you, content liked by You and information about the advertisements you have been shown or may have clicked on). You control the personal information You allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on the respective third party service and the permissions You give us when You grant us access to the personal information about You retained by the respective third party service. By associating an account managed by a third party with Your Recharge Duniya user profile and authorizing us to have access to this information, You agree that we may collect, use and retain the information provided by these third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. As an example, Recharge Duniya may send a queried telephone number to Twitter in order to verify it against the Twitter API or retrieve the holders’ Twitter ID or Twitter photo, if available. If the Twitter ID is available, Recharge Duniya will display a Tweet and follow button in the Users’ Recharge Duniya app, which the User may use to send an open tweet to, and start to follow, the holder of the number. The Recharge Duniya app is not, however, designed to be a Twitter communication application and You will not be able to retrieve the replied or further tweets to the Recharge Duniya app. When using the Twitter functionalities You are bound by the Twitter Terms of Service, located at https://twitter.com/tos, and the Twitter privacy policy, located at https://twitter.com/privacy.

4\. For the provision of free versions of the Services, Recharge Duniya may also collaborate with a few selected third party advertising networks, which in such case may be provided limited information related to the freemium User’s device (but no other User or Contact Information).

5\. Recharge Duniya, or a third party on its behalf, may collect and use your email address, telephone number and ID for advertising (including, but not limited to, content viewed by you, content you have commented on and information about the advertisements you have been shown or may have clicked on) through the Recharge Duniya Apps and share this information with third party advertisers and networks. Such third parties may use this information and information collected from other sources in order to provide measurement services and targeted ads. You can limit or opt-out of the collection and use of Your information for ad targeting by third parties via Your device settings.

The submission of Contact Information by You and the processing thereof by Recharge Duniya is constitutionally protected under the applicable law, see the Terms of Service. Recharge Duniya may, however, disclose information contained in the Service and about you if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance that disclosure of information is necessary, always provided, of course, it is also lawful.

Recharge Duniya may from time to time ask you to provide information on your experiences from using the Recharge Duniya Services, which will be used to measure and improve quality. You are at no time under any obligation to provide any of such data. Any and all information which is voluntarily submitted in feedback forms or any surveys that You accept to take part in is used for the purposes of reviewing this feedback and improving the Recharge Duniya software, products and websites.

Recharge Duniya servers may automatically collect data about Your Internet address when You use the Recharge Duniya Services. This information, known as an Internet Protocol address, or “IP Address”, is a number that is automatically assigned to Your computer or other device by Your Internet service provider whenever You are on the Internet. When You request pages from the Services, our servers may log Your IP Address and, if applicable, Your domain name. Your IP Address is used to help identify You and to gather demographic information about our Users as a whole. Recharge Duniya’s servers may also record the referring page that linked you to Recharge Duniya (e.g. another web site or a search engine); the pages You visit on the Services; the web site you visit after Recharge Duniya’s web site; the ads you see and/or click on; other information about the type of Web browser, computer, platform, related software and settings you are using; any search terms You have entered on this web site or a referral site; and other Web usage activity and data logged by Recharge Duniya’s servers. Recharge Duniya uses this information for internal system administration, to help diagnose problems with servers, and to administer our Services. Such information may also be used to gather demographic information, such as country of origin and Internet Service Provider.

Corresponding data may be collected and used for the same purposes when You enable and use the “search the web” functionality within the Recharge Duniya Apps.

Information Security

In order to provide the Recharge Duniya Services, Recharge Duniya may transfer, process and store personal data in a number of countries. Recharge Duniya may also subcontract processing of Your information to third parties located in countries other than Your home country. Information collected within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) may, for example, be transferred to and processed in a country outside of the EEA, which may not provide the same level of protection for personal data as within the EEA. You acknowledge and agree that Recharge Duniya may transfer Your personal data as described above for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. We take all reasonable precaution to protect Your information, Contact Information and other Content from misuse, loss and unauthorized access. Although we cannot guarantee this information will not be subject to unauthorized access, Recharge Duniya has physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in place to protect it. The Information is stored on secured servers and protected by secured networks to which access is limited to a few authorized employees and personnel. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

Accuracy of Collected Information

Recharge Duniya may on its own initiative, or at your request, replenish, rectify or erase any incomplete, inaccurate or outdated information retained by Recharge Duniya in connection with the operation of the Services. You have always the right to know what information is stored about You and have any data corrected or deleted on Your request, which should be submitted in accordance with our contact details below.

The accuracy and security of information concerning the Users and their contacts are Recharge Duniya’s highest priority and they are free to opt-in or opt-out of the Services at any time. You can delist Your telephone number from the Recharge Duniya database via a request directly on the Recharge Duniya website and if You choose to disable the Enhanced Search functionality or the Recharge Duniya Apps itself, all Contact Information will be made unavailable for search in the Recharge Duniya database.

Minors

Recharge Duniya Services are not intended for or designed to attract anyone under the age of 13 and Recharge Duniya does not intentionally or knowingly collect personal information in the Services from anyone under that age. We encourage parents to be involved in the online activities of their children to ensure that no information is collected from a child without parental permission.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

Recharge Duniya may at any time with or without a separate notice change this Privacy Policy, and You are encouraged to review this Policy from time to time. In case of substantial changes, Recharge Duniya notifies the Users by push notice or via notice on the Recharge Duniya website.
